JEAN-EMMANUEL KOUADIO

Shepherdstown, WV | (681)-283-0298 emmanuelkj5@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jean-emmanuel-kouadio-34b267186 Portfolio: https://jeanemmanuelk.github.jo/website/

SUMMARY

Organized and motivated Data analyst with experience collecting, cleaning, transforming, visualizing, and organizing data for analysis to help make informed decisions. Excellent understanding and proficiency in data analysis tools such as SQL, Excel, Tableau, R, and Python. Quick learner with a continuous improvement mindset and a solid drive to succeed. Aiming to add value to the company by utilizing data-driven insights and making data-informed recommendations.

SKILLS

Programming: MySQL | BigQuery | Python | R | GitHub.

Other: Effective presentation | Communication | Bilingual (English & French)

BI tools: Excel | Tableau | Power BI

EDUCATION

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, Online

Feb 2023

A 6 months rigorous training in data cleaning, manipulation, visualization, interpretation, and communication. (Tools: SQL, Excel, Tableau, R)

M.S. in Data Analytics & Information Systems, SHEPHERD UNIVERSITY, SHEPHERDSTOWN, WV

May 2024

• Courses: Big Data Analytics, Mathematical Modeling, Database Management, Statistical Analysis, Machine Learning, Data Mining, data visualization

B.S. In Computer Engineering, Shepherd University, Shepherdstown, WV

Dec 2021

• Courses: Operating Systems, Electrical Engineering, Networking, Computer Organization, Software Engineering, Circuit Design

PROJECTS

• Supplements Exploratory data analysis (EDA) - Bodybuilding.com: (Tools: Python)

In this project we are doing an EDA in order to find out the effect of the product (supplement) flavor on overall product rating and find useful insights. We found that the number of different flavors does affect the overall product rating. Also, the product pricing has a positive impact on the product rating. https://www.kaggle.com/code/jeanemmanuelkouadio/bodybuilding-com-supplements-eda

• Music Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) – Spotify music: (Tools: Python, R)

In this project we are exploring the music data from Spotify in order to run some data analysis and find useful insights answering a few questions like the most popular artists, the longest songs, the most popular genre. We found out that the loudness of the music has a positive impact on the energy of the music. https://www.kaggle.com/code/jeanemmanuelkouadio/spotify-music-data-analysis-project/notebook

• Sales Analysis – Adidas Sales: (Tools: Excel, Tableau, MySQL)

Collected adidas sales data from Kaggle and cleaned the data using Excel. Then used Tableau to import the data and get some visualizations of the sales data. https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/jean.emmanuel.kouadio/viz/addidasproject/Dashboard1

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sept 2022 – Present, Shepherdstown, WV

Flex manager, SHEPHERD UNIVERSITY WELLNESS CENTER

Manage a team of 3 employees including two lifeguards and one weight fitness. Responsible for daily operations of all facility areas including financial, risk management, equipment responsibilities, and the supervision of other student staff. I provide customer service to 1300+ community members and 1500+ students. Monthly sales have increased revenue by 10% over the previous year.

Jan 2018 – may 2022, Shepherdstown, WV

Resident Assistant. SHEPHERD UNIVERSITY RESIDENCE LIFE

Establish community, serve on call to ensure the safety and well-being of all residents within the residence hall, work on a team, conflict resolution, attend team meetings, execute events for residential students. Use several online systems and websites to submit reports, create event flyers, communicate with residents and team members, learn and receive new information, and work remotely during COVID-19.

Jan 2019 - Jul 2021, Shepherdstown, WV

Research Assistant, WV-INBRE BIO/CS/MATH/ENGR.

Conducted cancer research under the supervision of Dr. Qing Wang. Completed tasks such as mathematic analysis related to tumor growth subject to cancer therapy. Presented results at conferences, such as the West Virginia Academy of Science Conference.